Capron Family papers, 1777-1950.
Congregational Library & Archives
Capron Family papers, 1777-1950.
MS0044
Congregational Library & Archives
3.27 Cubic Feet
(6 boxes, 1 folder)
William Banfield Capron was born in Uxbridge, Massachusetts on April 14, 1824. Sarah Brown Hooker was born in Lanesboro, Massachusetts, on April 24, 1828. Sarah and William met while both were teaching at the Hartford High School. They were married on October 1, 1856. Almost immediately after their marriage, the couple were assigned to the Madurai (then called Madura) Mission of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. They worked in Madurai and Manamadurai until 1872. During this time, William and Sarah had three children, Annie Hooker (1860-1909), Laura Elizabeth (1862-1946) and Henry (1864-1865). They returned to the United States in 1872 before returning to India in 1874. William died of heart disease on October 6, 1876. Sarah continued to work in India until 1886. When she returned to the United States she continued to work with the Woman's Board of Missions, gave speeches, and in 1889 she began working with the Women's Department of the Bible Institute for Home and Foreign Missions in Chicago. She officially retired in 1894 and died on December 15, 1918. Central to the collection's papers are the letters of Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), William B. Capron, their daughters Annie H. Morse (née Capron) and Laura E. Keith (née Capron), and Sarah's sister, Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker). The collection primarily contains correspondence but also includes diaries and journals, manuscript writings, photographs and a family album, teak wood samples and a bead toy, publications and memorials, legal documents, and a fragment of a circa 1784 wedding dress.
Capron, Sarah B., 1828-1919
Capron, William B. (William Banfield), 1824-1876
Keith, Laura E., 1862-1946
Morse, Annie H., 1860-1909
Tufts, Anne E., 1830-1917
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by Winthrop P. Haynes in January, 1980. Additional materials were donated by Charles Haynes in May 1986. An accrual to the collection was made in 2001 by Calvin L. Traylor via the Bostonian Society (now Revolutionary Spaces). Three additional letters from William B. Capron were donated by Richael Potaski in July 2016.
Custodial History
A portion of the collection (see collection file for detailed inventory) was given to Calvin L. Traylor in 1976 by Robert and Ann E. Beckhold (née Keith). This portion of the collection was first donated to the Bostonian Society (now Revolutionary Spaces) in 2001 and then transferred to the Congregational Library & Archives not long after.
Three letters from William B. Capron were purchased at auction by Richael Potaski before they were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives in 2016. There is no additional provenance information for these letters, nor is it clear which letters these might be in the current iteration of the finding aid.
All other portions of the collection were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by direct descendants.
Biographical Note
William Banfield Capron was born in Uxbridge, Massachusetts on April 14, 1824, son of William Cargill Capron (1799-1875) and Chloe Capron (née Day) (1800-1882). He had three younger siblings, John Henry Capron (1827-1910), Samuel Mills Capron (1832-1874), and Laura Ann Washburn Biscoe (née Capron) (1837-1878). His education took him to the Phillips Academy, Yale, and the Andover Theological Seminary. He was an ordained Evangelist upon his graduation from Andover. While he was a student and seminarian, William was a private tutor in Baltimore for one year and principal of Hopkins Grammar School in Hartford, which merged into the Hartford High School, for six years.
Sarah Brown Hooker was born in Lanesboro, Massachusetts, on April 24, 1828, daughter of Henry Brown Hooker (1802-1881) and Martha Vinal Hooker (née Chickering) (1806-1893). She had two younger sisters, Anne Elizabeth Tufts (née Hooker) (1830-1917) and Martha Vinal Chickering Hooker (1836-1838). Sarah attended the Wheaton Female Seminary and the State Normal School at West Newton. She taught at the district schools of Falmouth and worked as a first assistant in the Oliver High School in Lawrence and later became an assistant in the Hartford High School.
Sarah and William met while both were teaching at the Hartford High School. They were married on October 1, 1856. Almost immediately after their marriage, the couple were assigned to the Madurai (then called Madura) Mission of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions (ABCFM); they set sail for India on November 21, 1856 and arrived about 100 days later. After their arrival in Madurai, Sarah was put in char of the Madura Girls' Boarding School while William performed evangelical work and supervised the construction of a house in Manamadurai. During this time, William and Sarah had three children, Annie Hooker (1860-1909), Laura Elizabeth (1862-1946) and Henry (1864-1865). The family moved to Manamadurai in 1864.
The family continued to work in and around Manamadurai, doing evangelical, medical, and educational work for the Madurai mission, until 1872. In 1872, William's and Sarah's requests for furlough were accepted and the whole family sailed back to the United States. During this time, William helped to write a publish a memorial book for his brother, Samuel Mills Capron, who had taken over as principal of the Hopkins Grammar School after William and died on April 1, 1874. Their furlough was ended in 1874 when Sarah and William sailed back to India to continue their work with the Madurai mission. Their daughters, Annie and Laura, remained in the United States under the care of Sarah's sister Anne and her husband Arthur Webster Tufts.
After returning to Madurai, Sarah took some medical lessons, before she and William returned to Manamadurai. In 1876, William suddenly died due to heart disease. Sarah remained in India, though she was reassigned to Madurai, to continue her work with the Madurai mission. She remained in India until 1886 when she retired from her foreign missionary work and returned to the United States. Her work with the ABCFM did not conclude though and between 1886 and 1889, Sarah worked with the Women's Board of Missions and traveled extensively to give speeches and talks about her missionary work to local missionary groups and churches.
In 1889, Sarah accepted the superintendent's position at the Women's Department of the Bible Institute for Home and Foreign Missions in Chicago (later the Moody Bible Institute). For five years she worked and lived in Chicago before retiring in 1894. After her retirement, she returned to Boston and lived with her sister Anne for many years. Eventually, likely due to their age, the two moved to Poughkeepsie to live with Laura and her husband James Dyer Keith (1864-1943). Anne died on April 9, 1917, and Sarah died on December 15, 1918.
The histories of Annie H. and Laura E. are significantly less well documented. Laura married her husband, James D. Keith on June 1, 1892. They had two children, James Monroe Keith (1893-1982) and Annie Hooker Hart (née Keith) (1895-1969). She and her husband lived in Poughkeepsie, and were well known within Poughkeepsie, until their deaths; Laura died on June 14, 1946.
Annie married her husband, Lewis Kennedy Morse (1869-1930), on April 21, 1897. They had two children, Anna Hooker Haynes (née Morse) (1899-1992) and Arthur Webster Morse (1900-1975). The documentary evidence shows that Annie's and Laura's families were very close, with both families visiting the other with some frequency. Annie died on October 31, 1909.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of the Capron Family. Central to the collection's papers are the letters of Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) and William B. Capron. Other prominent family members found in the collection include Sarah's sister, Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker), and Sarah's and William's daughters, Annie H. Morse (née Capron) and Laura E. Keith (née Capron). The collection primarily contains correspondence from the above five family members, as well as additional correspondence from the extended Hooker, Capron, and Keith families. The majority of the correspondence is familial in nature and, over the course of decades, documents the relationships and daily lives of five generations of family members. The collection also contains a number of diaries and journals. The collection also contains evidence of Sarah's and William's missionary work in Madurai, India, and at home through correspondence with the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, photographs, correspondence with family, and collected documents related to their missionary work. The collection at large contains correspondence, manuscript writings, photographs and a family album, teak wood samples and a bead toy, publications and memorials, legal documents, and a fragment of a circa 1784 wedding dress.
Arrangement
This series has been arranged into the below listed nine series. Generally speaking, materials were sorted into these series based primarily on the creator of the materials or the provenance of the materials. Materials within each series have been arranged in chronological order. At one point, most correspondence within the collection was sorted and foldered by recipient; as of 2024 most correspondence has now been sorted by the letter writer.
Series 1: Hooker Family papers, 1777-1856
Series 2: Capron Family papers, 1784-1929
Series 3: Anne Elizabeth Tufts (née Hooker), 1836-1910
Series 4: Sarah Brown Capron (née Hooker) papers, 1837-1919
Series 5: William Banfield Capron papers, 1840-1876
Series 6: Miscellaneous records, 1858-1928
Series 7: Annie Hooker Morse (née Capron), 1865-1909
Series 8: Laura Elizabeth Keith (née Capron), 1865-1950
Series 9: Photographic materials, 1882-1916
Related Materials
American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions Archives, 1810-1961 (ABC 1-91) Houghton Library, Harvard University.
Letter from Sarah B. Hooker to her parents, 1844, SMC-391. Marion B. Gebbie Archives and Special Collections, Wheaton College.
Sarah Brown Capron Letter, 1865 December 26, December 28, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Sarah Brown Hooker Capron papers, 1836-1900, Ms. Coll. 1488, Kislak Center for Special Collections, Rare Books and Manuscripts, University of Pennsylvania.
The Sarah Brown Hooker and William Banfield Capron Family Tree
The link below will bring you to a navigable family tree for Sarah and William Capron. The family tree includes 90 members across six generations, many of whom appear within the Capron Family papers collection. The collection is best understood when the relationships between the many correspondents found within are clearly denoted. We hope that this family tree will be helpful for your research while using the materials found within this collection.
The Sarah Brown Hooker and William Banfield Capron Family Tree
Bibliography
Elliot, Mary Elvira, Stimpson, Mary A., and Hoyt, Martha Seavey. Representative Women of New England. Edited by Julia Ward Howe. Boston: New England Historical Publishing Company, 1904.
Children of missionaries.; Diaries.; Genealogy.; Letters.; Missionaries -- India.; Missionaries' spouses.; Photograph albums.; Photographs.; American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions; Capron, Samuel Mills, 1832-1874; Chicago Evangelization Society. Bible Institute for Home and Foreign Missions; Hooker, H. B. (Henry Brown), 1802-1881; Hooker, John, 1729-1777; Lucy Perry Noble Bible School (Madurai, India); Tamil Nadu (India) -- Missions; Woman's Board of Missions
- Hooker Family papers, 1777 1856; 1777-1856; 1 Volume; 3 Folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records originating from the extended Hooker family. The majority of the records within this series were authored by Henry B. Hooker, the father of Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) and Anna E. Tufts (née Hooker). There is also a legal copy of the will of John Hooker, Sarah's and Anna's great grandfather.
  - John Hooker will (copy), 1777 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Henry B. Hooker correspondence, 1830 1836; 1830-1836 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Henry B. Hooker Index Rerum, 1830 1850; 1830-1850 (Box 1, Volume 12)
  - Henry B. Hooker to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1850 1856; 1850-1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Capron Family papers, 1784 1929; 1784-1929; 11 Folders
  This series contains the papers of the extended Capron family. The majority of the papers in this series are correspondence from William B. Capron's immediate family to William. A fragment of the wedding dress of Asenath Capron (née Cargil), William's grandmother, is also a part of this series.
  - Asenath Capron (née Cargil) wedding dress fragment, circa 1784 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Laura A. W. Biscoe (née Capron) to William B. Capron, 1839 1848; 1839-1848 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Samuel M. Capron to William B. Capron, 1840 1849; 1840-1849 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - William C. Capron to William B. Capron, 1841 1849; 1841-1849 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - John H. Capron to William B. Capron, 1843 1846; 1843-1846 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Chloe Capron (née Day) to William B. Capron, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Samuel M. Capron to Chloe Capron (née Day), 1852 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Samuel M. Capron to William B. Capron, 1857 1859; 1857-1859 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Laura A. W. Biscoe (née Capron), 1865 1869; 1865-1869 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - William C. Capron deeds (copy), 1894 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Laura Capron Green to Clara Day Capron, 1927 1929; 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Anne Elizabeth Tufts (née Hooker), 1836 1910; 1836-1910; 21 Folders
  This series contains the papers of Anne Elizabeth Tufts (née Hooker). The majority of the papers are letters written by Anne to family members, especially her sister, Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) and niece Laura E. Keith (née Capron). This series also contains miscellaneous letters sent to Anna and some letters from her husband, Arthur W. Tufts, and his family.
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) correspondence, 1836 1857; 1836-1857 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Henry B. Hooker, 1845 1855; 1845-1855 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Martha V. Hooker (née Chickering), 1846 1856; 1846-1856 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to aunt Vinal, 1848 1853; 1848-1853 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to uncle Vinal, 1849 1851; 1849-1851 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Anna H. Chickering (née Titcomb), 1850 1853; 1850-1853 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1885 1886; 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Martha V. Hooker (née Chickering), 1886 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Annie H. Morse (née Capron), 1886 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1886 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Arthur W. Tufts to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1889 1891; 1889-1891 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1889 1891; 1889-1891 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1903 1905; 1903-1905 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1906 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) correspondence, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Sarah S. Burke (née Tufts) to Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker), circa 1908 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1908 1909; 1908-1909 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Letters to Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Emma F. Powers (née Tufts) to Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to James D. Keith, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1910 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) poetry, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Sarah Brown Capron (née Hooker) papers, 1837 1919; 1837-1919; 35 Folders; 8 Volumes
  This series contains the papers of Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker). The majority of the papers in this series are letters written by Sarah to her immediate family members, especially her sister Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker) and her daughters Annie H. Morse (née Capron) and Laura E. Keith (née Capron). This series also contains journals, correspondence to Sarah, manuscript writings, and a book detailing the various addresses Sarah delivered.
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to aunt Vinal, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker), 1837 1857; 1837-1857 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Miss Mary Drew, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) correspondence, 1844 1856; 1844-1856 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) book of poetry, 1849 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) journal, 1852 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - First Congregational Society to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1852 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker), 1853 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Martha V. Hooker (née Chickering), 1853 1854; 1853-1854 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Anna H. Chickering (née Titcomb), 1853 1854; 1853-1854 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to aunt Vinal, 1853 1854; 1853-1854 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) journal (copy), 1856 1857; 1856-1857 (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - Sarah B. and William B. journal (correspondence), 1857 1866; 1857-1866 (Box 1, Volume 6)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) journal (copy), 1858 (Box 1, Volume 4)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) journal, 1858 1865; 1858-1865 (Box 1, Volume 5)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) Manamadurai correspondence, 1860 1884; 1860-1884 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Martha V. Hooker (née Chickering), 1863 1865; 1863-1865 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) Manamadurai correspondence, 1863 1868; 1863-1868 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Martha V. Hooker (née Chickering) and Anne E. Tufts (née Hooker), 1865 1883; 1865-1883 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) correspondence, 1880 1886; 1880-1886 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1885 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Autographs for Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1886 (Box 1, Volume 7)
  - S.P.C.K Press publications, 1887 1905; 1887-1905 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Addresses by Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1888 1889; 1888-1889 (Box 1, Volume 8)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) articles and writings, 1895 1902; 1895-circa 1902 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) biographies, 1895 1918; 1895, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) memorials, 1898 1919; 1898, 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1903 1905; 1903-1905 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Annie H. Morse (née Capron), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1906 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1908 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to James M. Keith, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Letters to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Clara Day Capron to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Alice M. St. John (née Biscoe) to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bertha C. Robbins (née Capron) to Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker), 1910 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1910 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Annie H. Hart (née Keith), 1910 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Sarah B. Capron (née Hooker) to Laura E. Keith (née Capron), 1914 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "The Mother and Daughter! A Peek into Hindu's Life" manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Ladies' Department of the Bible Institute for Home and Foreign Missions brochure, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- William Banfield Capron papers, 1840 1876; 1840-1876; 14 Folders; 3 Volumes
  This series contains the papers of William B. Capron. The majority of the papers in this series are letters written by William to his immediate family members, such as Samuel M. Capron and Laura A. W. Biscoe (née Capron). This series also contains letters written to the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, manuscript writings, letters written in Tamil, and additional letters addressed to William. A portion of William's correspondence while in India was collected into a correspondence journal which can be found in the Sarah Brown Capron (née Hooker) series.
  - William B. Capron to Chloe Capron (née Day), 1840 1847; 1840-1847 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous letters to William B. Capron, 1843 1849; 1843-1849 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - William B. Capron correspondence, 1856 1861; 1856-1861 (Box 1, Volume 9)
  - William B. Capron to Samuel M. Capron, 1856 1864; 1856-1864 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - William B. Capron correspondence, 1857 1868; 1857-1868 (Box 1, Volume 10)
  - William and Sarah Capron letters to the Sabbath school, 1861 1869; 1861-1869 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - William B. Capron to Laura A. W. Biscoe (née Capron), 1862 1865; 1862-1865 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - William B. Capron correspondence in Tamil, 1862 1869; 1862-1869 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - William B. Capron correspondence and diagrams, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - William B. Capron diary, 1865 1866; 1865-1866 (Box 5, Volume 1)
  - William B. Capron to Laura A. W. Biscoe (née Capron), 1865 1868; 1865-1868 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Copies of letters from William B. Capron to family, 1867 1868; 1867-1868 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - William B. Capron Jaffna correspondence, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - William B. Capron to Prudential Committee, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - William B. Capron manuscript writings on India, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - William B. Capron correspondence, 1874 1876; 1874-1876 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Articles following the death of William B. Capron, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous records, 1858 1928; 1858-1928; 7 Folders; 1 Volume; 7 Objects
  This series contains records and papers which, otherwise, do not fit the rest of this collection's series and whose provenance is unclear as to make it difficult to associate the materials with one particular person within the collection. A number of the papers are related to missionary work, and specifically, with the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. This series also contains a number of artifacts, including a bead toy, wood samples, and a teak dowel.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1858 1928; 1858-1928 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's record of the Ladies' Missionary Society, 1862 1885; 1860-1885 (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - David C. Scudder letters and letter from Alice A. Evans regarding David Scudder, 1861 1862; 1861-1862 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mary Susan Rice letters, 1863 1864; 1863-1864 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - H. W. Ballantine letter to Sabbath school, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Helen W. Reynolds, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous genealogy related clippings and documents, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Slap "Table Reminiscences", undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Teak dowel, undated (Box 5, Object 1)
  - Bead toy, undated (Box 6, Object 1)
  - Wood samples, undated (Box 6, Object 2-6)